Guide to the Northern Virginia Civil War images collection, 1853-1914
George Mason University Libraries
- Northern Virginia Civil War images collection
  - [Fairfax] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 15)
    - New York Firemen Zouaves Turning Out to Support Pickets Between Alexandria and Fairfax Courthouse, Virginia, June 22, 1861; 8.1B; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - Rescue of Captured Comrades by Second U. S. Cavalry at Fairfax, VA., 8.2; Wood Engraving; 7 1/4" x 9"
      Pictorial Battles of the Civil War
    - Lieutenant Tompkins, at the Head of Company B, U. S. Dragoons, Charging into the Town at Fairfax Court house, Killing Thirty of the Enemy and Carrying off Five Prisoners, in the Face of Fifteen Hundred Secession Troops, on Saturday, June 1, 1861, June 8, 1861, 8.3; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - Fairfax Court House, 8.5; Steel Engraving; 4 1/4" x 5 3/4"
      The Youths' History of he United States
    - U. S. Cavalry Scouting in the Neighborhood of Fairfax Court-House, VA., December 14, 1861, 8.7; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - U. S. Cavalry Scouting in the Neighborhood of Fairfax Court-House, VA., 8.8; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - Culpepper Court-House, or Fairfax, Capital of Fairfax County, Virginia, 8.9; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 13 3/4"
      by Edwin Forbes
    - United States Cavalry Scouting in the Neighborhood of Fairfax Courthouse, VA., 8.10; hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - Gallant Charge of Federal Cavalry Into Fairfax Courthouse, Virginia, June 22, 1861; 8.11A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - New York Firemen Zouaves Turning Out to Support Pickets Between Alexandria and Fairfax Courthouse, Virginia, June 22, 1861; 8.11B; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
  - [Falls Church] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 16)
    - The Village of Falls Church, VA. - Arrival of the Second U. S. Cavalry, Company B, Lieutenant Tompkins, on Wednesday Morning, June 19th, June 29, 1861, 10.1A; Wood Engraving; 6 1/4" x 9 1/4"
    - Arrival of the First and Second Connecticut Regiments at the Village of Falls Church, near Vienna, VA., on Wednesday Morning, June 19th, Subsequent to the Surprise of the Ohio Regiment by the Masked Secession Battery, June 29, 1861, 10.1B; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9 1/4"
    - The Village of Falls Church, VA. - Arrival of the Second U. S. Cavalry, Company B, Lieut. Tompkins, on Wednesday Morning, June 19th, 10.2; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6 1/4" x 9 1/4"
    - Bringing in the Misses Scott as Prisoners to Falls Church, VA., August 3, 1861, 10.3; Wood Engraving; 4" x 6 1/2"
    - The Civil War in America: Skirmish near Fall's Church, Virginia, December 21, 1861, 10.4; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 3/4"
    - President McKinley Reviewing the Volunteers at Camp Alger, May 28. 13,000 Soldiers of the 2d Army Corps March past the President and Major-General Miles at Falls Church, Virginia, 10.5; Reproduced Painting; 8 1/2" x 13"
      by W. Peters; Harper's Weekly
    - A Confederate Scout Watching Union Troops near Fall's Church, VA., 10.6; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6 1/2" x 9 1/4"
      Pictorial War Record
    - "A Confederate Treed" - Capture of Lieutenant H. J. Segal of the Confederate Army near Falls Church, 10.7; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - "A Rebel Treed" - Capture of Lieutenant H. J. Segal of the Insurgent Army near Falls Church by Lieutenant-Colonel Winslow and Captain Shattuck of the New York 37th, October 26, 1861; 10.9; Wood Engraving
    - Unsere Flotille auf dem Potomac-Fluffe, zwischen Freestone-Point, Virginien, und Indian Head, Maryland, 10.10A; Wood Engraving; 4 1/4" x 20"
    - Taylor's Wirthshaus in Falls Church, Virginien, das Hauptquartier des Generals Smith, Befehtshaber der Unionstruppen, 10.10B; Wood Engraving; 5 1/4" x 20"
    - Anficht von Falls Church, Mason's Hill und Hmgegend. Aufgenommen in den Verschanzungen unferer Truppen auf Munson's Hill, 10.10C; Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 20"
  - [Falmouth] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 17)
    - The Camp of the Twelfth Massachusetts Regiment, near Falmouth, Virginia, May 16, 1863; 3.2; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - The Camp of the Twelfth Massachusetts Regiment, near Falmouth, Virginia, May 16, 1863; 3.13; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - Goldaten-Friedhof nahe bem Lager bei Falmouth am Rappahannod, Birg, 20.35; Wood Engraving
  - [Fredericksburg] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 18)
    - The Attack on the Rebel Works at Fredericksburg by the Centre Grand Division of the Army of the Potomac, on December 13, 1862, Janurary 3, 1863, 3.1A; Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 13 1/2"
    - Fredericksburg on the Night of 11th December, 1862 Janurary 3, 1863, 3.1B; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 13 1/2"
    - Passage of the Rappahannock by the Grand Army of the Potomac at Fredericksburg, VA., Wednesday, Midnight, December 10th, 1862, 3.2A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14 1/4"
    - Federal Baggage Train on Its Way to the Army at Falmouth, VA., December, 1862, 3.2B; Wood Engraving; 14 1/2" x 9"
    - Burnard's House; Doubleday's Skirmishers; Franklin's Division Recrossing the River; The Battle of Fredericksburg - The Artillery Covering the Retreat, January 10, 1863, 3.3; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
      by T.R. Davis; Harper's Weekly
    - Bombardment of Fredericksburg, Va., by the Army of the Potomac, Commanded by General Burnside. Thursday, December 11th, 1862, 3.4A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14 1/4" x 20"
      by H. Lovie; The Soldier in Our Civil War
    - Map of the Battle of Fredericksburg December 13th 1862, 3.4B; Wood Engraving; 12 3/4" x 9 1/2"
      by Walter A. Lane; The Soldier in Our Civil War
    - Effect of the Bombardment of Fredericksburg - Federal Soldiers on Guard, 3.4C; Wood Engraving; 6 1/4" x 9 1/4"
      by Henry Lovie; The Soldier in Our Civil War
    - Terrific Charge of the Federal Troops (Sumner's Division) upon the Confederate Fortifications Located on the Terrace Behind Fredericksburg, VA., December 13th, 1862, 3.5A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14 1/2" x 20"
    - The Grand Army Recrossing the Rappahannock from Fredericksburg to Falmouth, Monday Night, December 15th, 1862, 3.5B; Wood Engraving; 6 1/4" x 9"
    - Lower Part of Fredericksburg, Falmouth; Wrecks of Steamers Burned by the Rebels; Stockaded Bridge and Blockhouse; Tomb of Washington's Mother; Ruins of the Rail Road Bridge; The City of Fredericksburg and its Vicinity, December 6, 1862, 3.6; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 13 3/4" x 20 1/2"
    - Fredericksburg, Virginia, December 20, 1862, 3.8; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14" x 20 1/4"
    - Fredericksburg from Falmouth, November 1862, 3.9; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - Gallant Charge of Humphrey's Division at the Battle of Fredericksburg, 3.10; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
      by Mr. A. R. Waud; Harper's Weekly [Same image as 3.12 in folder 18]
    - The Battle of Fredericksburg: Assault of the Federals on Marye's Hill and the Battery of the Washington Artillery, January 31, 1863, 3.11; Wood Engraving
    - Gallant Charge of Humphrey's Division at the Battle of Fredericksburg, 3.12; Wood Engraving
      by Mr. A. R. Waud; Harper's Weekly [Same image as 3.10 in folder 18]
  - [Fredericksburg II] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 19)
    - The Army of the Potomac - At and on the Way to Fredericksburg, December 13, 1862, 3.7; Wood Engraving; 14" x 20 1/2"
  - [Gaines's Mills] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 20)
    - Battle of Gains's Mills, Four O'Clock in the Afternoon, Friday, June 27th, 1862, 20.4A; Chromolithograph; 2 1/4" x 8"
    - Battle of Willis Church, 10 O'Clock A.M., Monday, June 30th, 1862 - Generals Hancock, Heintzelman, Sumner, and Porter's Forces Engage Generals Jackson, Longstreet and A.P. Hill, 20.4B; Chromolithograph; 2 3/4" x 8"
    - The Army of the Potomac - Captain de Hart's Battery Shelling the Rebel Advance at the Battle of Gaines's Mills, June 27, 1862, July 19, 1862, 20.5; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
      Harper's Weekly [same image as 20.6 in folder 20]
    - The Army of the Potomac - Captain de Hart's Battery Shelling the Rebel Advance at the Battle of Gaines's Mills, June 27, 1862, July 19, 1862, 20.6; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
      Harper's Weekly [same image as 20.5 in folder 20]
  - [Hall's Hills] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 21)
    - The Bright Side of the War - Holiday Festivities of the 44th New York Volunteers at Their Camp, Hall's Hill, Virginia, January 18, 1862, 20.25; Wood Engraving; 14" x 19 1/2"
  - [Harrison's Landing] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 22)
    - General View of the Encampment of the Army of the Potomac at Harrison's Landing, August 23, 1862, 20.8; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 13 3/4"
  - [Langley] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 23)
    - Campaign on the Potomac - Guard House near Langley, VA., with Rebel Prisoners, February 1, 1862, 9.1; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
  - [Leesburg] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 24)
    - Central View of Leesburg, 13.1; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 2 1/2" x 3 3/4"
      Loudon County
    - Camp in the Woods near Leesburg, Loudon County, Virginia - Virginia Infantry, November 9, 1861, 13.2; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 5" x 9"
  - [Lewinsville] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 25)
    - The War in America: Bringing in the Federal Wounded after the Skirmish at Lewinsville Virginia, October 12, 1861, 9.1; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 13 1/2"
    - The War in America: Bringing in the Federal Wounded after the Skirmish at Lewinsville Virginia, October 12, 1861, 15.6; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 13 1/2"
  - [Manassas] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 26)
    - A. Commencement of the Battle at Bull's Run; B. Firing into Deserted Earth-Work near Bull's Run, August 3, 1861, unnumbered; Wood Engraving
      Harper's Weekly [Same as image 2.21B and 2.21C in folder 26]
    - Major-General M'Clellan, Major-General McDowell, and Staffs, Escorted by the Fifth Cavalry, Crossing Bull Run at Blackburn's Ford, March 29, 1862, unnumbered; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 20"
      by Mr. A. R. Waud; Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.20A in folder 26]
    - Bridge over Bull Run, near Blackburn's Ford, Burned by the Rebels, March 29, 1862, unnumbered; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 10"
    - Evacuation and Firing of Manassas Junction by the Rebels, March 29, 1862, unnumbered; Wood Engraving; 5 3/4" x 10"
    - Virginia - The Battlefield of Bull Run Revisited, October 15th by Union and Confederate Officers. Scenes and Incidents of the Visit, October 27, 1883, unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - Dedication of the Monument on the Battle-Field of Bull Run, Virginia, July 15, 1865, unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - Great Battle at Bull's Run between the Federal Army, Commanded by Major-General McDowel, and the Rebel Army under Jefferson Davis, Gen. Beauregard and Gen. Johnston, Sunday, July 21, 1861 - Advance of the Federal Troops, August 3, 1861, 2.1; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - The Battle of Bull Run, VA., Sunday, July 21st, 1861 - The Federal Army Advancing, 2.2A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9" x 14"
      The Soldier in Our Civil War [Same image as 2.32A in folder 26]
    - The First Michigan Regiment and the Ellsworth Zouaves in the Entrenchments at Alexandria, VA., 2.2B; Wood Engraving; 8" x 9 1/4"
      The Soldier in our Civil War [Same image as 2.32B in folder 26]
    - Federal Baggage-Train of Pope's Army Making Their Way toward Manassas Junction, 2.3A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14 1/2" x 9"
    - Showing the Position of the Troops, Preparatory to the Second Battle of Bull Run, August 30th, 1862, 2.3B; Wood Engraving; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"
    - Manassas Junction after its Evacuation by the Confederates, February, 1862, July, 1861, 2.4; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 13 3/4"
      Harper's History of the Great Rebellion
    - Monument Erected on the Field of the First Battle of Bull Run, July 1, 1865, 2.5A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6" x 9"
    - Consecration of the Bull Run Monuments - Reading the Service, June 11, 1865, July 1, 1865, 2.5B; Wood Engraving; 3" x 9"
    - The War in Virginia - Officers and Men of Meade's Army Discovering Unburied Federal Dead on the Old Battlefield of Bull Run, 2.7; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - View of the Battlefield of Second Bull Run, as Sketched in August, 1863, 2.8A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 8 3/4" x 14"
      by Edwin Forbes; The Civil War in the United States
    - The Army of the Potomac Passing over Their Old Battle-Ground at Manassas, VA., 2.8B; Wood Engraving; 6 1/2" x 9 1/4"
    - Retreat of Our Troops from Bull Run, by Moonlight. Colonel Blenker's Brigade Covering, August 10, 1861, 2.9; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - The Rebels Bayanetting Our Wounded on the Battlefield, at Bull Run, August 17, 1861, 2.10; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - The Battle at Bull's Run - The Gallant Sixty-Ninth, N. Y. S. M., Assaulting a Rebel Battery Masked with Bushes, and Carrying It at the Point of the Bayonet, August 3, 1861, 2.11; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
    - Charge of the Black Horse Cavalry upon the Fire Zouaves at the Battle of Bull Run, August 10, 1861, 2.12A; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
      Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.31 in folder 26]
    - Carrying in the Wounded at the Battle of Bull Run, August 10, 1861; 2.12B; Wood Engraving; 6 3/4" x 9 1/4"
    - Silencing the Enemy's Batteries at the Battle of Bull Run, August 10, 1861, 2.12C; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
    - Jackson's "Foot-Cavalry" at the Second Bull Run, 2.13
      by Allen C. Redwood; Journal Article with Print Reproductions
    - The Second Battle of Bull Run, 2.14
      by John Pope; Journal Article with Print Reproductions
    - First Battle of Bull Run, 2.15; Hand Colored Steel Engraving; 5" x 7 1/2"
      by W. Momberger and J. C. McRae; Abbotts Civil War
    - The War Game at Manassas - Views of the Troops in Camp Taken by Our Special Photographers, 1904, 2.16; Reproduced Photograph; 10" x 7"
      by Penfield
    - The War in Virginia - General Hooker's Army Marching past Manassas, VA., June, 1863, 2.17; Wood Engraving; 6 3/4" x 10 1/4"
      by Mr. Edwin Forbes
    - Manassas-Junftion mit den derlaffenen feindlichen Erdiverfen, den zurucfgelaffenen Wagen und Ruinen des Eifenbahn-Depots, 2.18; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9" x 14"
    - Great Battle at Bull's Run, VA. Fought on Sunday, July 21, between the Federal Army Commanded by Gen. McDowell, and the Rebel Army Commanded by Jeff. Davis, Generals Beauregard A. D. Johnston, August 3, 1861, 2.19; Wood Engraving; 14" x 20"
    - Major-General M'Clellan, Major-General McDowell, and Staffs, Escorted by the Fifth Cavalry, Crossing Bull Run at Blackburn's Ford, March 29, 1862, 2.20A; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 20"
    - Bridge over Bull Run, near Blackburn's Ford, Burned by the Rebels, March 29, 1862, 2.20B; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 10"
    - Evacuation and Firing of Manassas Junction by the Rebels, March 29, 1862, 2.20C; Wood Engraving; 5 3/4" x 10"
    - Colonel Hunter's Attack at the Battle of Bull's Run, August 3, 1861, 2.21A - 2.21D; Wood Engraving; 14" x 20 1/4"
    - General Sigel's Corps at the Second Battle of Bull Run, September 20, 1862, 2.22; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 13 3/4" x 20 1/2"
      by Mr. Davenport; Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.34 in folder 26]
    - The Civil War in America: The Last Stand made by the Federals at Manassas, November 15, 1862, 2.23; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7 1/4" x 20"
    - The War Game at Manassas - Snap-Shots of incidents and Scenes During the Military Manoeuvre on the Battle-Field of Bull Run: Signal Corps Men Putting in Telephone Wires at the Headquarters Tent of the Second Brigade; The Eighth Massachusetts, Major Stapper Leading, Marching over a hill near Hay Market; On the Firing-Line - A Scene near Belcher's Farm; On the Firing-Line - Troops on Bull Run Battle- Field, 2.25; Reproduced Photographs; 7 1/4" x 10 1/2"
      by Penfield; Harper's Weekly
    - The Naval Battery (Rebel) at Manassas Junction, September 14, 1861, 2.26; Wood Engraving; 9" x 14"
    - An Incident in the Retreat at the Battle of Manassas, 2.27; Steel Engraving; 5" x 7 1/4"
      by F. O. C. Darley and W. Ridgway
    - Bull Run - Stand of the Union Troops at the Henry House. 3 P.M., 2.28; Hand colored wood engraving; 5 1/2" x 8"
      by P. Meeder
    - Die Schlacht bei Bull Run, Virginien. Angriss der Feuerwehr-Buaben auf eine feindliche Batteries Nach einer Skizze unfres Kunstlers, welcher die Diviston des Generals McDowell begleitete, 2.30A; Hand colored wood engraving; 14" x 19 1/2"
    - Parte des Kriegsschauplakes in Virginien [Map, Petersburg, VA to Seneca Mills, MD], 2.30B; Wood engraving; 9 1/4" x 7"
    - Manassas Junction Looking towards Bull Run and Centreville, taken from the Parapet of the Fortifications to the Southwest of the Railway Depot, showing the Various Fortifications and Headquarters of the Rebels, etc, October 12, 1861, 2.35; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
  - [Manassas II] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 27)
    - Second Day of the Second Battle of Bull Run, Fought Saturday, August 30 -- The National Forces Commanded by Major General Pope, and the Rebel Troops by Generals Lee, Jackson and Longstreet, September 20, 1862, unnumbered; Hand colored wood engraving; 9 1/2" x 29 1/4"
    - Charge of the Black Horse Cavalry upon the Fire Zouaves at the Battle of Bull Run, August 10, 1861, 2.31; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 14"
      Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.12A in folder 26]
    - The Battle of Bull Run, VA., Sunday, July 21st, 1861 - The Federal Army Advancing, 2.32A; Wood Engraving; 9" x 14"
      The Soldier in Our Civil War [Same image as 2.2A in folder 26]
    - The First Michigan Regiment and the Ellsworth Zouaves in the Entrenchments at Alexandria, VA., 2.32B; Wood Engraving; 8" x 9 1/4"
      The Soldier in our Civil War [Same image as 2.2B in folder 26]
    - The Military Manoeuvres at Manassas - Scenes and Incidents by our Special Photographers, 2.33; By Burr McIntosh; Reproduced photographs
    - General Sigel's Corps at the Second Battle of Bull Run, September 20, 1862, 2.34; Wood Engraving; 13 3/4" x 20 1/2"
      by Mr. Davenport; Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.22 in folder 26]
    - A. The Army of the Potomac - The Great Depot of Supplies on the Railroad; B. The Army of the Potomac - The Bridge over Bull Run - Present Appearance, December 12, 1863; 2.36; Wood Engraving
    - Monument Erected on the Field of the First Battle of Bull Run, July 1, 1865, 2.37; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9"
      Harper's Weekly [Same image as 2.5A in folder 26]
    - Manassas Junction After its Evacuation by the Confederate Army - Abandoned Fortifications, Camps, Wagons and Burned Railroad Depots, 2.38; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
      By Edwin Forbes; The Civil War in the United States
  - [Manassas III] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 28)
    - The Second Battle of Bull Run, Fought Aug. 29th 1862, 2.24; Hand Colored Lithograph; 8 1/2" x 12"
      by Currier and Ives
  - [Maps] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 29)
    - Map from Gettysburg, Pennsylvania to Fredericksburg, Virginia, 21.2; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6 3/4" x 4"
      by Fisk and Russell; History of the Great Rebellion
    - Map Showing the Shenandoah Valley, 21.3; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6 3/4" x 4 1/4"
      The Civil War
    - Map of Bull Run and Environs, 21.4; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 5 3/4" x 4 1/2"
      Civil War in America/ War and Its Horrors
    - Rebel Position at Centreville: Reconnaissance of March 14th, 1862, 21.5; Lithograph; 6 1/4" x 10"
      by M. D. McAlester
    - Operations of the Army of Virginia under Maj. Gen. John Pope: Position of Troopson the Night of August 27th, 1862, 21.6; Lithograph; 7" x 9 1/2"
      by Julius Bien and Co.
    - Danville, Virginia to Williamsport, Maryland, 21.10; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 3 3/4" x 6 3/4"
      History of the Great Rebellion
    - Map of Washington and Environs, 21.11; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 5" x 4 1/2"
      Civil War in America, War and Its Horrors
    - Portions of the Middle Department, 2nd Division 8th Army Corps, 21.13; Lithograph; 9" x 10 1/2"
      by Capt. W. Angelo Powell
    - Southeastern Virginia (From the Potomac to the Chickahominy), February, 1862, 21.15; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
    - Operations in Northern Virginia, 21.16; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 10 1/4" x 9 1/4"
    - Map of the Valley of Virginia from Staunton to Winchester, 21.17; Lithograph; 16 1/4" x 7"
      by P. W. O. Koerner
    - Battle-Field of Young's Branch or Manassas Plains. Battle Fought July 21st, 1861, June 1, 1871, 21.18; Lithograph; 10" x 9"
      by Maj. N. Michler
    - Map of the Seat of War in Virginia, Showing the Theatre of Operations of Gens. Hooker, Dix, and Keyes, and the Scene of Gen. Stoneman's Raid, May 23, 1863, 21.19; Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
    - Potomac River at Washington, D.C., Map Showing Condition of Work, June 30, 1896, 21.20; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7 3/4" x 28 3/4"
      by Andrew B. Graham Photo-Litho
    - Rand McNally Junior Auto Road Map of Delaware Maryland Virginia West Virginia, 21.21; Lithograph; 11 1/4" x 17 1/4"
      by Rand McNally and Co.; Commercial Atlas
    - The Rand McNally New Commercial Atlas of Virginia, 21.23; Lithograph; 18 3/4" x 25 3/4"
      Rand McNally
    - The Rand McNally New Commercial Atlas of Virginia, 21.24; Lithograph; 18 3/4" x 25 3/4"
    - United States Department of the Interior Geological Survey Vienna Quadrangle Virginia-Maryland, 1951, 21.37; Lithograph; 22 3/4" x 17 3/4"
      by the Geological Survey; U.S. Geological Survey
    - United Stated Department of the Interior Geological Survey Falls Church Quadrangle Virginia-Maryland, 1956, 21.38; Lithograph; 22 1/2" x 17 3/4"
  - [Maps II] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 30)
    - Historical Map of Virginia and Adjacent Maryland Showing the Main Points of Historic Interest and the Main Traveled Automobile Routes, 1949; 21.1; Lithograph; 15" x 32 3/4"
      American Automobile Association
    - Territory between Baltimore and Ohio R.R. and Manassas Gap R.R., Maryland and Virginia, 21.7; Lithograph; 5 1/4" x 8"
      by L. L. Poates
    - The Seat of Military Operations in August and September, 1862 [Gordonsville to Harpers Ferry], 21.8; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7 1/4" x 4"
      History of the United States
    - Operations in North Eastern Virginia, Maryland, and Pennsylvania, 21.9; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7" x 4 1/4"
      Operations in Northeastern Virginia
    - Seat of War in Virginia - Showing the Recent [?]rations of the National and Rebel Armies, September 13, 1862, 21.12; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14 1/4" x 9"
    - Southeastern Virginia, February, 1862, 21.14; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
    - Map of Northeastern Virginia and Vicinity of Washington, August 1, 1862, 21.27A; Lithograph; 16 1/4" x 27"
      by J. J. Young and W. Hesselbach; Surveys for Military Defenses, Sheet 1
    - Map of Northeastern Virginia and Vicinity of Washington, August 1, 1862, 21.28A; Lithograph; 16 1/4" x 27"
      by J. J. Young and W. Hesselbach; Surveys for Military Defenses, Sheet 2
    - Map of Northeastern Virginia and Vicinity of Washington, August 1, 1862, 21.29; Lithograph; 16 1/4" x 27"
    - No. 1 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Positions of the Camps and Pickets of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., May 3d, 1864, and the Routes of March from May 4th to May 21st, 1864, to the Battles of the Wilderness and Spotsylvania C. H., VA., 21.31A; Lithograph; 7 1/2" x 11"
      Top Engr. Office, V.D.
    - No. 5 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes and Positions of the 2d Coprs, A. N. VA., from May 21st to May 27th, 1864, 21.31B; Lithograph; 11" x 8"
    - No. 7 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes, Camps,and Positions of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., from May 27th to June 13th, 1864, 21.31C; Lithograph; 10 1/2" x 8 1/4"